Guide to the Beer Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- THOMAS BEER, 1909-1936; Series IX; 2" (1 box)
  - Published Writings
    - Saturday Evening Post
      - "Thirty-Five Minutes", 1931 March 14 (Box 156, Folder 13)
      - "Luxury", 1931 May 16 (Box 156, Folder 14)
      - "The Devil Listened", 1931 May 30 (Box 156, Folder 15)
      - "Mnemosyne", 1932 April 30 (Box 156, Folder 16)
      - "Nero Had Him Three Wives", 1933 December 16 (Box 156, Folder 17)
      - "Gregrampa", 1934 January 13 (Box 156, Folder 18)
      - "Haircuts on Friday", 1934 June 9 (Box 156, Folder 19)
      - "The Intellect and Society", 1934 July 21 (Box 156, Folder 20)
      - "Anniversarial", 1934 October 6 (Box 156, Folder 21)
      - "Cousin Judith", 1934 December 29 (Box 156, Folder 22)
      - "See Page 299", 1935 April 27 (Box 156, Folder 23)
      - "Read to Kitty Shapiro", 1936 August 11 (Box 156, Folder 24)
    - Century Magazine
      - "The Enemy", 1922 May (Box 156, Folder 25)
- ALICE BALDWIN BEER, 1740-1981; Series X; 6' (15 boxes & 1 folio)
  Arrangement of this series is intended to parallel the organization of material in SERIES IV of the initial donation of Beer Family Papers.
  Correspondence is divided into two sub-sections: Thomas and Richard Beer's Writings and Personal. Each section is arranged alphabetically by individual and/or topic.
  Cooper Union Museum Files is arranged alphabetically by individual or topic as well.
  - Correspondence, Thomas and Richard Beer's Writings
    - American Mercury, 1943 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Atlantic Monthly - general, 1942-1944 (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - Atlantic Monthly, "This Written Word", 1943-1944; undated (Box 157, Folder 3-5)
    - Atlantic Monthly, "Recollections of a Writer", 1943-1944 (Box 157, Folder 6-10)
    - Beer, Richard - biographical and bibliographic data, 1959; undated (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - Beer, Richard - sketch of Thomas Beer, undated (Box 157, Folder 12)
    - Beer, Thomas
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 157, Folder 13)
      - Book jackets, undated (Box 157, Folder 14)
      - Cassettes - Alice Baldwin Beer analyzes T. Beer's letters of 1914-1917 [transferred to Historical Sound Recordings], 1974 (Box 157, Folder 15)
      - Clippings, [ca. 1910-1948] (Box 157, Folder 16-18)
      - Early editions, 1972 (Box 158, Folder 19)
      - Notes for biography, undated (Box 158, Folder 20)
      - Plays, 1972-1973 (Box 158, Folder 21)
      - "Thomas Beer, As Seen by Two Classmates," by Monty Wooley and Cary Abbott, Saturday Review of Literature, 1941 (Box 158, Folder 22)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew J., 1967-1968; 1977 (Box 158, Folder 23)
    - Cabell, Mrs. James Branch, 1950-1972 (Box 158, Folder 24)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (re: Evans Harrington), 1966 (Box 158, Folder 25)
    - Coyle, William D. - "The Short Stories of Thomas Beer," Ph.D. dissertation, 1977 (Box 158, Folder 26-27)
    - Cusik, Mrs. Peter, 1972-1973 (Box 158, Folder 28)
    - Ernst, Morris, 1971; 1976 (Box 158, Folder 29)
      See also: box 158, folder 35-36
    - Ernst, Morris (re: Evans Harrington), 1966 (Box 158, Folder 30)
    - Fisher, Harold H. (re: Evans Harrington), 1966 (Box 158, Folder 31)
    - Friedel, Frank, 1975 (Box 158, Folder 32)
    - Garfunkel, George, 1970; 1971-1972 (Box 158, Folder 33)
    - Green, Dorothy, 1941; 1971-1972 (Box 158, Folder 34)
    - Greenbaum, Wolff, and Ernst, 1958-1959 (Box 158, Folder 35-36)
    - Greenbaum, Wolff, and Ernst, 1960-1975 (Box 159, Folder 37-40)
      See also: box 158, folder 29
    - Griffin, Marie (re: Richard Beer), 1973 (Box 159, Folder 41)
    - Harrington, Evans, 1966-1969; 1973 (Box 159, Folder 42)
      See also: box 158, folder 25 See also: box 158, folder 29 See also: box 161, folder 110-111 See also: box 159, folder 44 See also: box 159, folder 46-47 See alos: box 160, fodler 61
    - Henry, Grace (re: Richard Beer), 1973 (Box 159, Folder 43)
    - Housum, Robert, 1937; 1966-1969; 1972-1977; 1981 (Box 159, Folder 44)
    - Housum, Robert (re: Evans Harrington), 1966-1968; 1973 (Box 159, Folder 45)
    - Knopf, Alfred A. (Publishers), 1941-1981 (Box 159, Folder 46-47)
    - Knopf, Alfred A. (re: Evans Harrington), 1966-1968 (Box 159, Folder 48)
    - Knopf, Christopher, 1957 (Box 159, Folder 49)
    - Libraries
      - Columbia University, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 50)
      - Harvard University, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 51)
      - Louisiana State University, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 52)
      - New York Public Library, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 53)
      - Newark Public Library, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 54)
      - Princeton University, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 55)
      - University of Arkansas, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 56)
      - University of North Carolina, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 57)
      - University of Virginia, 1972 (Box 159, Folder 58)
    - Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1945-1947 (Box 160, Folder 59)
    - Library of Congress, Copyright Office -certificates of registration, 1947-1958 (Box 160, Folder 60)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1970; 1973 (Box 160, Folder 61)
    - Mumford, Lewis (re: Evans Harrington), 1966 (Box 160, Folder 62)
    - Ober, Harold (Associates), 1953-1957 (Box 160, Folder 63)
    - Piggott, William, 1973 (Box 160, Folder 64)
    - Saturday Evening Post - copyright, 1944 (Box 160, Folder 65)
    - Simon, Linda, 1975 (Box 160, Folder 66)
    - Smith, Mrs. James Nichols, 1972 (Box 160, Folder 67)
    - Vollenweider, Jorg, 1968-1973 (Box 160, Folder 68)
    - Wheeler, Mrs. Reginald, 1972 (Box 160, Folder 69)
    - Yale University
      - Classmates of Thomas Beer - lists, 1940; 1952; 1972-1973 (Box 160, Folder 70)
      - Donation of books, 1968; 1972-1974 (Box 160, Folder 71)
      - Donation of papers, 1940-1947; 1954-1968; 1972-1979 (Box 160, Folder 72-75)
      - Gift agreements, 1972-1976 (Box 160, Folder 76)
      - Kahn, Herman, 1972-1975 (Box 160, Folder 77)
      - Maslyn, David, 1972-1973 (Box 160, Folder 78)
    - Yankee Magazine (re: Richard Beer), 1973 (Box 160, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence, Personal
    - Abbot, Cary, [ca. 1945-1947] (Box 161, Folder 80)
    - Appelman, Mark J., 1953 (Box 161, Folder 81)
    - Archibald, Ann and John, 1959; 1964; 1974-1976 (Box 161, Folder 82)
    - Author and Writer's Who's Who, 1947 (Box 161, Folder 83)
    - Author's League, [ca. 1946] (Box 161, Folder 84)
    - Barnes, Edward Labaree, 1973 (Box 161, Folder 85)
    - Barnes, Margaret Fawcett, 1980 (Box 161, Folder 86)
    - Boynton, Frederick Perry, 1947 (Box 161, Folder 87)
    - Brown, Curtis (Ltd.), 1951-1957 (Box 161, Folder 88)
    - Byne, Mildred Stapley - estate, 1938-1971 (Box 161, Folder 89-94)
    - C (Box 161, Folder 95)
    - Civic affairs, 1972-1977 (Box 161, Folder 96)
    - Cooke, Allistair, 1974 (Box 161, Folder 97)
    - Crowley, Alice L., 1945; 1949-1951; 1971-1972 (Box 161, Folder 98)
    - Crowley, Herbert Edmond, 1938-1939 (Box 161, Folder 99)
    - Cummings, Abbott, 1971 (Box 161, Folder 100)
    - Daybook, 1946-1947 (Box 161, Folder 101)
    - Deeds and mortgages, 1903; 1925; 1940 (Box 161, Folder 102)
    - DeRay Bookbinding Company, 1972-1973 (Box 161, Folder 103)
    - Dinsmore, William A., 1952 (Box 161, Folder 104)
    - DuBois, Theodora, 1966; 1969 (Box 161, Folder 105)
    - Du Pont, Harry, undated (Box 161, Folder 106)
    - E (Box 161, Folder 107)
    - Edwards, Joan, 1970-1979 (Box 161, Folder 108)
    - European trip, 1925 - notes (Box 161, Folder 109)
    - Fisher, Harold H., 1967-1975 (Box 161, Folder 110-111)
      See also: box 162, folder 124
    - Fisher, Harold H. - printed material, 1951-1952 (Box 161, Folder 112)
    - Fisher, Harold H. and Helen, 1953-1954 (Box 162, Folder 113)
    - Fisher, Helen, 1941-1942; 1956; 1959 (Box 162, Folder 114)
    - Fisher, Tony, 1974; 1976 (Box 162, Folder 115)
    - Follett, Wilson, 1945-1948 (Box 162, Folder 116)
    - G (Box 162, Folder 117)
    - Gardiner, Alice and Raymond, 1939; 1945; 1959; undated (Box 162, Folder 118)
    - Glazier, Claire, 1977-1978, undated (Box 162, Folder 119)
    - H (Box 162, Folder 120)
    - Hall, Charles H., 1978 (Box 162, Folder 121)
    - Hill, Mabel Hall, 1961 (Box 162, Folder 122)
    - Hondius-Crone, A. H., 1969-1973; undated (Box 162, Folder 123)
    - Hoover Library, Stanford University, 1931; 1942 (Box 162, Folder 124)
      See also: box 161, folder 110-111
    - Housum, Robert, 1941-1960; 1975; 1979-1987 (Box 162, Folder 125)
    - J (Box 162, Folder 126)
    - Johnson, David, 1972-1977; undated (Box 162, Folder 127)
    - Jurow, Martin, 1947 (Box 162, Folder 128)
    - K (Box 162, Folder 129)
    - Kaufman, Robert, 1975-1976 (Box 162, Folder 130)
    - Knopf, Alfred, 1966-1967; 1972; 1977; 1981 (Box 162, Folder 131)
    - Leonard, Elizabeth, 1969-1975; undated (Box 162, Folder 132)
    - Letters of introduction, 1910-1911 (Box 162, Folder 133)
    - Lewisohn, Irene and Leonard - estate, 1944-1945 (Box 162, Folder 134)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1944; 1947; 1967-1968; 1972 (Box 162, Folder 135)
    - Minniegerode, Meade and Mildred, 1947; 1967 (Box 162, Folder 136)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 162, Folder 137)
    - Montgomery, Charles F., 1976-1979 (Box 162, Folder 138)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1972-1973; 1979 (Box 162, Folder 139)
    - Museum of Costume Art, 1938 (Box 162, Folder 140)
    - Museums, 1947; 1963; 1970-1974 (Box 162, Folder 141)
    - N (Box 163, Folder 142)
    - Nantucket Historical Association, 1970-1973 (Box 163, Folder 143)
    - Nantucket Conservation Foundation, 1974-1977 (Box 163, Folder 144)
    - Needle and Bobbin Club, 1968; 1973-1974 (Box 163, Folder 145)
    - Netherlands, 1969-1970 (Box 163, Folder 146)
    - New York Public Library, 1970-1975 (Box 163, Folder 147)
    - Ober, Harold, 1946; 1953 (Box 163, Folder 148)
    - P (Box 163, Folder 149)
    - Palmer, Margaret, 1957 (Box 163, Folder 150)
    - Passports, 1924-1956 (Box 163, Folder 151)
    - Peter Cooper Village - Stuyvesant Town, 1971-1976 (Box 163, Folder 152)
      See also: box 164, folder 171
    - Pettit, Florence, 1969-1973 (Box 163, Folder 153)
    - Pocket Books, Inc., 1940-1946 (Box 163, Folder 154)
    - Possessions - lists, undated (Box 163, Folder 155)
    - R (Box 163, Folder 156)
    - Rambo, James, 1950-1980; undated (Box 163, Folder 157-160)
    - Schindler, Kurt, 1933-1972; undated (Box 164, Folder 161)
    - Siasconset property, 1903-1976 (Box 164, Folder 162-166)
    - Smith, Harvey, 1968; 1973 (Box 164, Folder 167)
    - Smith, Howard Ross, 1970-1975 (Box 164, Folder 168)
    - Stark, Ray, 1947-1948 (Box 164, Folder 169)
    - Stowell, Donald, 1973 (Box 164, Folder 170)
    - Stuyvesant Town, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1952; 1957-1960 (Box 164, Folder 171)
    - Sullivan, Frank, 1947 (Box 164, Folder 172)
    - Taylor, Donald, 1971 (Box 164, Folder 173)
    - Taylor, Lisa, 1976 (Box 164, Folder 174)
    - Thurman, Lawrence, 1973 (Box 164, Folder 175)
    - Tilghman, James D., [ca. 1939]; 1945-1946; 1972-1976; undated (Box 164, Folder 176-177)
    - Tuttle, Emerson and Holly, 1941-1943; 1948; 1973; undated (Box 164, Folder 178)
    - Tyler family, 1968; 1971-1975; undated (Box 164, Folder 179)
    - Van Lowen, Jan, 1947 (Box 164, Folder 180)
    - Venezuela Speculations, Inc., 1928 (Box 164, Folder 181)
    - Vevier, Charles, 1959 (Box 164, Folder 182)
    - Von Nagy, Amelie, 1949 (Box 164, Folder 183)
    - Walcott, Sue J., 1956 (Box 164, Folder 184)
    - Weissberger, Jose A. - estate, 1954-1955; 1959; 1975; undated (Box 164, Folder 185)
    - Wheeler, Rex, 1952; 1956; 1964; undated (Box 164, Folder 186)
    - White, G. B., 1974 (Box 164, Folder 187)
    - Wilk, Ruth, 1946 (Box 164, Folder 188)
    - Willis, Betty, 1957-1958 (Box 164, Folder 189)
    - Woolley, Monty, 1947 (Box 164, Folder 190)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum Files
      - Bibliographies - textiles, fabrics, embroidery, undated (Box 165, Folder 191)
      - Clippings, 1963; 1976 (Box 165, Folder 192-193)
      - Committee to Save the Cooper Union Museum - general, 1962-1963 (Box 165, Folder 194)
      - Committee to Save the Cooper Union Museum - Lewis Mumford, 1963 (Box 165, Folder 195)
      - Correspondence, general, 1962-1972 (Box 165, Folder 196)
      - Donation of personal library to museum, 1976 (Box 165, Folder 197)
      - Donors to the Textile Department, 1963 (Box 165, Folder 198)
      - "Dress Materials and Fabrics 1700-1900: A Glossary", 1960 (Box 165, Folder 199)
      - "El Panteon Real de las Huelgas de Burgos", 1952 (Box 165, Folder 200)
      - Hare, Constance, undated (Box 165, Folder 201)
      - Hathaway, Calvin S. - biographical sketch, [ca. 1975] (Box 165, Folder 202-206)
      - Howell, Josephine, 1972 (Box 165, Folder 207)
      - Irvin, John - notes on block printing in western India, 1957 (Box 166, Folder 208)
      - Lectures
        See also: box 168, folder 239-242
        - Chicago, Illinois, 1964 (Box 166, Folder 209)
        - Dearborn, Michigan, 1966 (Box 166, Folder 210)
        - Deerfield, Massachusetts, 1965 (Box 166, Folder 211)
        - Des Moines, Iowa, 1965 (Box 166, Folder 212)
        - "Frances Little", undated (Box 166, Folder 213)
        - Norfolk, [Virginia?], undated (Box 166, Folder 214)
        - Philadelphia Museum, 1960 (Box 166, Folder 215)
        - Raynham Hall, 1961 (Box 166, Folder 216)
        - "Threads of History", 1966 (Box 166, Folder 217)
        - "Trade Goods", 1970 (Box 166, Folder 218)
        - Tryon Palace Commission, New Bern, North Carolina, 1970-1971 (Box 166, Folder 219-221)
        - "Why Textiles", undated (Box 166, Folder 222)
        - Williamsburg, Virginia, 1954 (Box 166, Folder 223)
      - Mumford, Lewis, 1971 (Box 166, Folder 223)
        See: box 165, folder 194
      - Nevinson, John L., 1971 (Box 166, Folder 224)
      - Notes, undated (Box 166, Folder 225)
      - Notes on the history of the Cooper Union Museum and the Cooper Hewitt Museum, 1976-1977 (Box 167, Folder 226)
      - Prints
        - New York Public Library, undated (Box 167, Folder 227)
          See also: box 171A, folder 242
        - Old Sturbridge Village, 1969 (Box 167, Folder 228)
        - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1969 (Box 167, Folder 229)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 167, Folder 230)
      - Publications - Bulletin de la Societe Industrielle de Mulhouse, 1966-1967 (Box 167, Folder 231)
      - Publications - Cooper Union Museum, 1919-1949; [ca. 1959-1961] (Box 167, Folder 232-233)
      - Publications - Cooper Union Museum, Chronicle, 1943-1963 (Box 167, Folder 234)
      - "Report of Self Evaluation", [ca. 1958] (Box 167, Folder 235)
      - Rutledge, Anna Wells - "After the Cloth was Removed", undated (Box 167, Folder 236)
      - Smithsonian Institution - 30 year certificate, 1978 (Box 167, Folder 237)
      - Traite sur les Toiles Peintes …, by M.Q***, 1740 (Box 168, Folder 238)
      - Slides, 35 mm. color
        - "Cloth" (Box 168, Folder 239)
        - "Chintz" (Box 168, Folder 240)
        - "Spices," "India," and miscellanea (Box 168, Folder 241)
        - "Lecture slides" (Box 168, Folder 242)
      - Notebooks (Box 169, Folder 242)
      - Notebooks (Box 170, Folder 242)
      - Notebooks (Box 171, Folder 242)
      - Prints - New York Public Library (Box 171A, Folder 242)
        See also: box 167, folders 227-230
- RICHARD CAMERON BEER, 1895-1958; Series XI; 5" (1 box)
  Arrangement of this series is intended to parallel the organization of material in SERIES V of the initial donation of Beer Family Papers.
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  Personal Files is arranged alphabetically by individual and/or subject.
  - Correspondence
    - 1957-1958 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Unpublished Writings
    - "Along This Road", undated (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - "David and the Thimble Tiger", undated (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - "From the Other Side of the Wall", 1951 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - "Gentle Judas", undated (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - "The Home Life of the Giant Cactus", undated (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - "Horizon-Breaker", undated (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - "Jano-Bacsi", undated (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - "The Little Wind and the Mystery of Ole Man Onus", undated (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - "The Peculiar People of Port Enet", 1956 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - "Strategy", 1955 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - "The Wave Who Made Good", 1956 (Box 172, Folder 12)
  - Personal Files
    - Beer, Doris - water color sketches, undated (Box 172, Folder 13)
    - Beer, Doris - pencil sketches, undated (Box 172, Folder 14)
    - Beer, Doris and Richard - original illustrations for Heritage Press editions of Emerson's poems, undated (Box 172, Folder 15)
    - "Life and Adventures of an Arkansas Doctor," by David Rattlehead, 1895 (Box 172, Folder 16)
    - Nantucket miniatures - pen and ink sketches, by Richard Beer, undated (Box 172, Folder 17)
    - "Wave" illustrations, undated (Box 172, Folder 18)
- OVERSIZE
  - Judge Thomas Beer: scrapbook (Box 173)
  - William Collins Beer: scrapbook of European trip, 1913-1914 (Box 174)
  - Linus Caleb Baldwin: ledger, 1883-1888 (Box 175)
  - 2 photograph albums: European trip, 1911 (Box 176)
  - Photographs (Box 177)
  - Glass slide negative (4) (Box 178)
  - Books
    - Stephen Crane (7 copies) (Box 179)
    - Hanna (3 copies) (Box 179)
    - The Road to Heaven (4 copies) (Box 179)
    - The Mauve Decade (2 copies) (Box 179)
    - Sandoval (1 copy) (Box 179)
    - Mrs. Egg & Other Barbarians (1 copy) (Box 179)
    - Mrs. Egg & Other Americans (1 copy) (Box 179)
    - A Battle in Greece, by Stephen Crane (1 copy) (Box 179)
    - Prize Stories of 1922 (1 copy) (Box 179)
  - Materials from Series I-VI (Box 180)